片 名: 丁丁历险记: 独角兽号的秘密
Very nearly there, sir.
就快完成了 先生
I have to say, your face is familiar. Have I drawn you before?
看你很面熟 我以前画过你吗
Occasionally.
偶尔吧
Of course! I've seen you in the newspaper.
肯定见过啦 英国报纸上
- You're a reporter? - I'm a journalist.
- 你是通讯员? - 我是记者
Be patient, Snowy, not much longer.
耐心点 白雪 就快好了
I do beg your pardon.
真不好意思?
There.
好了!
I believe I have captured something of your likeness.
我觉得还是有抓到你的一些特点
Not bad!
不错!
What do you think, Snowy?
你觉得怎么样 白雪?
Snowy!
哦 白雪
There you are, sir.
给您的 先生
Now where's he run off to?
他去哪了?
Anything?
有消息吗?
Nothing.
一无所获
Snowy!
白雪!
Where have you been?
你去哪了?
Chasing cats again?
又去追喵星人了?
Snowy, look at this!
白雪 看这个
Triple masted.
三桅船
Double decks. Fifty guns.
双层甲板 50门炮
Isn't she a beauty?
是不是很漂亮
That's a very unique specimen, that is. From an old sea captain's estate.
这可是一艘很独特的样品 是一位老船长的遗物
"The Unicorn."
独角兽号
Unicorn. Man o'war sailing ship.
没错 独角兽号帆船战舰
It's very old, that is. 16th century.
可有年头了 造于16世纪
17th, I would think.
我觉得是17世纪
- Reign of Charles I. - Charles II.
- 查尔斯一世统治时期 - 查尔斯二世
That's what I said, Charles II. As fine a ship as ever sailed the seven seas.
我说的就是查尔斯二世 这可是艘纵横七大洋的好船
You won't find another one of these, mate.
别的地儿可见不到的 小哥
And it's only two quid.
只要2镑
- I'll give you a pound. - Done!
- 我出一镑 - 成交
Gently does it.
小心点
Excuse me!
让下
Here you go. Careful.
给你 拿好了
Hey, bud, how much for the boat?
嘿 老哥 这艘船怎么卖?
I'm sorry, I just sold it to this young gent.
抱歉 已经卖给这位小兄弟了
Oh, yeah?
是吗?
Tell me what you paid and I'll give you double.
你花了多少 我加倍给你
- Double? - Thanks. But it's not for sale.
- 双倍? - 谢了 但我不卖
Look, kid, I'm trying to help you out.
嘿 小兄弟 我是想帮你
I don't think you realise this,
你好像不知道
but you're about to walk into a whole mess of danger.
你就要大祸临头了
What kind of danger?
什么祸?
I'm warning you, get rid of the boat and get out while you still can.
我提醒你 趁早把这船扔掉 趁你还可以时
These people do not play nice.
那些家伙不好惹
What people?
什么人
Wonderful!
真漂亮
It's just wonderful.
着实漂亮
Don't bother wrapping it, I'll take it as is. Does anybody object if I pay by cheque?
不用包装 我直接要了 有人反对我付支票吗
If you want to buy it, you'll have to talk to the kid.
你想买的话 就得和这个孩子商量了
I see.
明白了
Well, let the "kid" name his price.
好吧 那就让孩子出价吧
"Name his price"?
出价?
Ten years I've been flogging bric-a-brac
我做古董生意10年了
and I miss "name your price" by one bleedin' minute!
就差这一分钟 这好事就是我的了
I'm sorry. I already explained to the other gentleman.
不好意思 我已经和那位先生解释过了
American he was. All hair oil and no socks.
美国佬 一头油发 没穿袜子
It's not for sale.
这船不卖
Then let me appeal to your better nature.
我来说的明白些
I have recently acquired Marlinspike Hall,
我刚买下了马林斯派克大厅
and this ship, as I'm sure you're aware, was once part of the estate.
和这艘船 你也知道这些资产曾是一位
Of the late sea captain?
一位老船长
The family fell upon hard times. Lost everything.
他们家遭遇不幸 什么都没了
They've been living in a cloud of bad luck ever since.
他们一直霉运不断 自从...
We are talking generations of drinking and irrational behaviour...
我们说的可是他们家几代人的酗酒 荒谬行为...
I'm sorry.
不好意思
But as I told you before, it's not for sale.
我已经说过了 这船不卖
Good day to you, sir.
祝您愉快
That young man, what's his name?
那个年轻人 叫什么
Him? Everybody knows him. That's Tintin.
人人都认识他 他是丁丁
What is it about this ship?
这艘船有什么神秘之处?
Why has it attracted so much attention?
为什么这么多人关注它
What secrets do you hold?
你都藏了什么秘密呢
Where is that magnifying glass?
放大镜在哪?
I could have sworn it was...
可能是...
(记者丁丁揭开匪徒部落神秘面纱)
(记者揭秘犯罪团伙)
(丁丁勇夺国家文物 失窃艺术品重归博物馆)
(国王重夺王权 丁丁在西尔达维亚授奖)
Snowy, you haven't seen the...
白雪 你看见...
Where is it?
放哪了?
Thank you.
谢谢你
No, Snowy!
不 白雪
Look what you did.
看你干的好事
You broke it!
摔坏了
Bad dog!
坏狗狗
Something happened on this ship.
这艘船有蹊跷之处
And we're going to the one place that could have the answer.
只有一个地方能找到答案了
Come on, Snowy.
走了 白雪
Here it is.
找到了
"Sir Francis Haddock of Marlinspike Hall,
马林斯派克大厅的主人 弗朗西斯・阿道克爵士
the last captain of the ill-fated Unicorn."
不幸独角兽号的最后一位船长
"The ship set sail from Barbados in 1676"
船起航于 1676年 巴巴多斯
"on one of the most ruinous voyages in maritime history."
这是航海史上最悲惨的远航之一
"Ship never reached destination."
这艘船未能到达目的地 途中遭遇海盗袭击
"Attacked by pirates, all hands lost except for one survivor."
只有一个幸存者 其他船员全部遇难
"When Sir Francis was rescued and returned home,"
弗朗西斯船长获救 回到家乡后
"he was convinced his name had been cursed."
他深信自己的名字被诅咒了
"The Unicorn's manifest stated"
独角兽号自称
"that it was carrying a cargo of rum and tobacco bound for Europe,"
装载朗姆酒和烟草前往欧洲
"but it was long claimed the ship was carrying a secret cargo."
但更多人相信 "独角兽号装运了一批神秘货物"
What was the ship carrying, Snowy?
这艘船到底装的是什么呢 白雪
"Historians have tried and failed to discover
"历史学家 试图揭秘这次致命航行中
what happened on that fatal voyage,"
到底发生了什么事情 但失败了"
"but Sir Francis' last words,"
弗朗西斯的遗言是
"'Only a true Haddock will discover the secret of the Unicorn."
真正的阿道克后人 才能破解独角兽号的秘密
I've missed something, Snowy.
遗漏了些什么 白雪
We need to take a closer look at that model.
我得再仔细看看那艘模型
Of course it's gone!
肯定是不见了
How could I be so stupid?
我怎么这么蠢
How'd you do that?
你是怎么做到的
Clever boy.
真是聪明
A coat of arms.
一枚纹章
Why does that look familiar?
怎么这么熟悉
Hang on a minute.
等等
That fish!
那条鱼
It's a haddock.
是黑线鳕
Of course! Marlinspike Hall is the old Haddock estate.
这豪宅是老阿道克的
Snowy!
白雪
Well done, Snowy!
干的好 白雪
Good boy.
好样的
Well, well, well.
哦 好了
It seems we've caught our thief.
抓到贼了
Welcome to Marlinspike Hall.
欢迎来到马林斯派克大厅
I see you let yourself in.
我看见你进来了
I came to retrieve my property.
我是来拿回我自己的东西
I'm sorry, I'm not sure I follow you.
我好像没明白你的意思
I think you do.
你明明知道
This ship was stolen from my apartment less than an hour ago.
不到1小时前 有人从我家偷走了这艘船
I'm afraid you're mistaken, Mr Tintin.
恐怕你搞错了 丁丁先生
There's no mistake. It belongs to me.
没有错 这是我的
Are you sure?
你确定吗
Of course I'm sure.
当然确定
I took it home, I put it on a cabinet in the living room,
是我买回家的 我把它放在起居室的橱柜上
and then Snowy chased the cat and knocked it over, and it
白雪追逐猫时 碰倒了
fell.
摔坏了
This isn't my ship.
这不是我的船
No. Indeed.
的确不是
I'm sorry.
抱歉
- It looks identical. - Well, looks can be deceiving.
- 看起来很相像 - 足够以假乱真了
Yes, indeed. But I don't understand!
没错 我不明白
Why did Sir Francis make two ships exactly alike?
弗朗西斯为什么要做两艘一模一样的船呢
And you have one already. Why do you want another?
你已经有一艘了 干嘛还想要另一搜?
What is it about this model that would cause someone to steal it?
这艘模型有什么特别之处 引得贼人觊觎
Goodness me, why so many questions?
天呐 这么多问题
It's my job.
这是我的工作
There could be a story here. That's what I do, you see.
可以写成一个故事 我很轻松就能完成
Well, it's no great mystery.
这没什么神秘的
Sir Francis Haddock was a drunkard and a hopeless reprobate.
弗朗西斯・阿道克是个酗酒无可救药的无赖
He was doomed to fail, and he bequeathed that failure to his sons.
他注定要失败 并把失败遗传给自己的儿子们
So it's true! The Haddock line is cursed.
原来是真的 阿道克家族被诅咒了
- What else have you found out? - What is there to find?
- 你还查到了些什么 - 还有什么可查的?
That depends what you're looking for.
那就取决于你在寻找些什么了
I'm looking for answers, Mr Sakharine.
我寻找答案 萨卡林先生
You're looking in the wrong place.
你找错地方了
It's late.
时间不早了
I think you should go home.
你该回家了
This way, sir.
这边 先生
It's a pity, sir.
真遗憾 先生
I'm sorry?
什么
That the mast broke on your model ship, sir.
你那艘模型上坏掉的船桅
I hope you found all the pieces.
希望你找到全部碎片了
Things are so easily lost.
这些东西很容易弄丢的
Nestor! Where are you?
内斯特 你在哪
Good night, sir.
晚安 先生
Some things are easily lost.
"有些东西很容易弄丢"
What did he mean by that, Snowy?
这话是什么意思
What was he trying to tell me?
他想告诉我什么
Some things are easily lost.
"有些东西很容易弄丢"
Snowy!
白雪
Great snakes!
天呐
What is it, Snowy?
是什么 白雪
What's this?
这是什么
This was in the mast!
这是船桅里的
Good boy, Snowy.
好孩子 白雪
"Three brothers joined."
三兄弟一道驾
"Three Unicorns in company"
三艘独角兽号
"sailing in the noonday sun will speak."
于正午时分航行在太阳下
"For 'tis from the light that light will dawn."
会有阳光射下
"And then shines forth the Eagle's Cross."
照亮雄鹰十字架
What are these markings?
这是什么?
Some kind of secret language or code?
某种秘密语言或是密码
It makes no sense.
没有道理
But it does explain why they ransacked the flat.
不过倒是解释了他们为什么洗劫了公寓
They were looking for this, and they didn't find it.
他们是要找这个却没找到
Which means
也就是说
they'll be back.
他们会回来的
No, I don't know where he is, dearie. I think he's gone out.
我不知道他在哪 德瑞 他大概是出门了
And anyway, it's after dark,
晚上过了睡觉时间
and Mr Tintin is most particular about not admitting visitors after bedtime.
丁丁先生最不喜欢见客人
I have to go back to my cocoa.
我要回去喝可可了
I've got a very good book and a cup of cocoa.
我有一本好书和一杯可可
It's really lovely!
真的很棒
Thank you, Mrs Finch. I can look after this.
谢谢你 芬奇太太 我来处理吧
Hey, kid, is that you? Open the door.
孩子 是你吗 开门
What do you want?
你想干嘛
Look, the game is up. He's gonna be back.
听着 游戏已经开始了!他要回来了
Now, I know he wanted those boats, but I swear to God,
我知道你想要这些船 但我发誓
I never thought he'd kill anyone over it!
我从没想到他会为此不惜杀人
Who? Who are you talking about?
谁?你说的是谁?
I'm trying to tell you that your life is in danger.
我想告诉你 你现在很危险
Answer me! Who?
回答我 是谁?
Mrs Finch! A man's been shot on our doorstep!
芬奇太太 有人在门阶中枪了
- Not again. - Call an ambulance!
- 现在吗? - 叫救护车
No, Snowy!
够了 白雪
Can you hear me?
你能听到我说话吗
Can you...
能吗
The victim's name was Barnaby Dawes.
遇害者名叫巴纳比・道斯
He was one of the top agents at Interpol,
是国际刑警组织高级探员之一
but we haven't got a clue what he was working on.
但我们还不清楚 他在忙些什么
Quite right, Thompson. We're completely clueless.
没错 汤姆森 我们完全没线索
Interpol doesn't have any other leads?
国际刑警组织没有别的发现吗
Steady on, Tintin. We're still filling out the paperwork.
丁丁 我们还忙着处理书面工作
Police work's not all glamour and guns. There's an awful lot of filing.
警察工作并不只是开开枪简单!还有很多书面工作
Well, I might have something for you.
我有些事情要告诉你们
Before he lost consciousness, Dawes tried to tell me something,
在他失去意识之前 他想告诉我一些什么
and I think he was spelling out a word.
我觉得他在拼一个词
"B-O-U"
"D-J-A-N."
"Karaboudjan."
卡拉布让
Karaboudjan!
Does that mean anything to you?
你知道这是什么意思吗
Great Scotland Yard! That's extraordinary!
伟大的苏格兰场!难得啊!
What is?
什么
Worthington's have a half-price sale on bowler hats!
沃森汀斯的圆顶硬礼帽半价
Really, Thomson! This is hardly the time.
真的吗? 可真难得啊
- Great Scotland Yard! - What is it?
- 伟大的苏格兰场 - 什么啊
Canes are half-price, too!
手杖也是半价
Are you going to take charge of this evidence?
你要带走这份证据吗
Positively.
当然
Never fear, Tintin, the evidence is safe with us!
别担心 丁丁 证据在我们这儿很安全
Thomson? Where are you?
汤姆森 你怎么了?
Well, I'm already downstairs. Do try to keep up.
我已经下楼了 快跟上
Wait! You dropped this.
等等 你掉了这个
Good heavens, Thomson! Look after the evidence, man.
小心证据
Sorry, Thompson. My mind is on other things.
抱歉 汤普森 我在想别的事情
Yes. Our light-fingered larcenist.
哦 对 手法熟练的小偷
- What? - The pickpocket.
- 什么?- 那个扒手
He has no idea what's coming.
他还不知道要大祸临头了
Go on, Tintin, take my wallet.
试试 丁丁 来拿我的钱包
Yes, industrial strength elastic.
没错 工业强度橡皮筋
Very resourceful.
非常聪明
On the contrary. It was childishly simple.
另一方面 也是非常的简单
Simply childish, I agree.
相当幼稚 我同意
- Tintin. - Tintin.
- 丁丁 - 丁丁
Gentlemen.
先生们
Mind you, I expect he's miles away by now.
听着 我觉得他离我们有几里地远
I presume you're referring to the pickpocket?
我想你是指扒手吧
Yes. I mean, knowing we're just a few steps behind him.
我们离他只有几步远
Snowy, what is it, boy? What do you see?
白雪 怎么了 你看见什么了
I don't suppose you'd fancy a cup of tea?
你好像不想喝杯茶
You're quite mistaken. I'd love one.
你可错了
My treat.
我请客
- I've got you now! - You devil!
抓到你了 站住
Stop, in the name of the law!
抓到你了
Got you!
What's going on down there?
那边发生什么了
Come on, Snowy!
走 白雪
- I do beg your pardon. - Sorry, sir!
- 不好意思 - 对不起 先生
The pickpocket, Tintin! He's getting away!
那个扒手 丁丁 他要跑了
My wallet!
我的钱包
It's gone!
不见了
Come on! Snowy, after him!
上 白雪 那边
Stop! Wait!
站住 等等
- Got you! - Steady on.
- 抓住你了 - 站稳了
I've lost him!
我追丢了
You must find my wallet. It's very important. I have to get it back.
你们一定要找到我的钱包 很重要 我必须找回来
And you will. Leave it to the professionals.
你会的 交给我们专业人士吧
We've lost the scroll.
纸卷丢了
But we haven't lost the story.
但故事没丢
"Karaboudjan."
卡拉布让
It's an Armenian word. That's our lead, Snowy.
是个亚美尼亚字
What was Barnaby Dawes trying to tell us when he said our lives were in danger?
这是线索 白雪 巴纳比・道斯 想告诉我们什么?
- Mr Tin... Tin? - Yes.
- 丁...丁先生 - 嗯?
- Delivery for you. - But I didn't order anything.
- 有你的快递 - 可我没订过什么啊
Well, that's because it's you that's getting delivered!
没错 因为要送的就是你
(卡拉布让号)
Quick, get him in the van!
快点 装上货车
Get off me, you confounded mutt!
松开 你这杂种
He bit me!
他咬我
Quick!
快
Get him Off!
快走 快走
Shake him off, then run him over!
把它甩掉
I want this on the starboard side!
我想它在右舷
Not here. Look your side.
不在这 看你那边
Hang on.
等等
- Nothing. - Well, check that pocket, Tom.
- 什么都没 - 检查那边口袋
No, I've looked in this one already, I'm sure of it.
我已经搜过了 我肯定
Well, have a look in his socks.
翻他袜子了吗
- Have you found it? - He doesn't have it.
- 找到了吗 - 不在他身上
It's not on him, boss. It's not here.
不在他身上 不在这
- Not here? Then where is it? - Where's what?
- 不在这儿 那在哪儿 - 什么在哪儿
I am tired of your games. The scroll, from the Unicorn.
我厌倦你的把戏了 独角兽号上的纸卷
A piece of paper like this!
一张纸 像这个
You mean the poem?
你是说那首诗
Yes.
没错
- The poem written in Old English. - Yes.
- 一首用古英语写的诗 - 对
- It was inside a cylinder. - Yes.
- 在一个圆筒里 - 没错
- Concealed in the mast. - Yes!
- 藏在船桅里 - 正是
I don't have it.
我弄丢了
You know the value of that scroll. Why else would you take it?
你不明白那纸卷的价值 你要它干嘛?
Two ships and two scrolls, both part of a puzzle.
我有点不解 两个纸卷 只是谜语的一部分
You have one, you need the other.
你有一个了 还需要另一个
But that's not it. There's something else.
不是这样 还有别的
I will find it, with or without your help.
我会找到的 不论你帮不帮忙
You need to think about exactly how useful you are to me.
你想清楚自己对我有多大用处
- We'll deal with him on the way. - Aye-aye, sir.
- 我们在路上处理他 - 是 是 先生
Hold this course.
保持航向
Snowy!
白雪
It's good to see you, too. See if you can chew through these ropes.
见到你可真高兴 看能不能咬开绳子
He's lying! He must have the scroll. The question is, what has he done with it?
他在撒谎 纸卷一定在他那儿 问题是他做了什么
We searched him all over, boss.
我们已经搜过他了 老板
I want you to go back down there and make him talk.
我要你回去 让他开口
Break every bone in his body if you have to!
有必要的话敲碎他每一根骨头
That's nasty.
那可够狠的
You know the stakes. You know what we're playing for. Just do it!
你知道风险 你也知道我们在干什么 快去做
Mr Sakharine! Mr Sakharine! All hell has broken loose!
萨卡林先生!萨卡林先生!出大事了
It's a disaster! The captain has come around.
麻烦来了 船长醒了
- What? - He's conscious.
- 什么? - 他清醒了
He's accusing you of mutiny.
他骂你哗变
- He says you turned the crew against him. - Sounds like he's sobered up again.
- 策反船员反对他 - 好像他又清醒明白了
Well, don't just stand there. Get him another bottle.
别光站这儿 再给他瓶酒
Ave, sir!
是 先生
- Jiggle it a bit, it's just stuck. - Jiggle?
- 晃一晃 卡住了 - 晃晃?
What are you doing? Get off!
你干吗呢 让开
It's not stuck, you idiot. He's bolted it from the inside!
没卡住 你个白痴 是他在里面把门闩上了
So you want to play like that then, do you, Tintin?
你想和我们玩玩 是吧 丁丁
Get the TNT.
去拿炸药
Broken crates. Rope. Champagne.
破箱子...绳子...香槟
What else do we have, Snowy?
还有什么 白雪
There are other ways to open this door.
一定有别的办法开门
They'll be swabbing the decks with your innards when we're done with you.
等我们抓到你了 要拿你的内脏刷甲板
Give it here.
放这儿
- Don't move. - What...
- 别动 - 什么
Let's go!
我们上
Let me have him!
抓住他
He's got a big shooter!
他有一把大枪
He got me!
我中弹了
Hold your fire.
停火
He ain't here. He's vanished.
他不在这儿 消失了
He's hiding.
他藏起来了
Search the ship. Quickly!
搜船 快!
A giant rat of Sumatra!
一只大老鼠从窗户跳进来
So, you thought you could sneak in behind me
啊哈 你觉得可以溜到我背后
and catch me with my trousers down, huh?
扒我的裤子吗
I'd rather you kept your trousers on, if it's all the same to you.
您还是留着裤子吧
- I know your game. You're one of them. - Sorry?
- 我知道你的把戏 你跟他们一伙 - 什么?
- They sent you here to kill me, huh? - Look, I don't know who you are!
- 他们派你来杀我 - 我都不认识你
That's how he's planned to bump me off.
他们派你来除掉我
Murdered in my bed by a baby-faced assassin!
派一个娃娃脸来刺杀我
Assassin? Look, you've got it all wrong.
刺客!你搞错了
I was kidnapped by a gang of thugs.
我也是受害者 被人绑架了
The filthy swine.
那头肮脏的猪
He's turned the whole crew against me!
他策反所有船员
Who?
谁?
A sour-faced man with a sugary name.
那个叫萨什么的老酸脸
He's bought them all off, every last man.
他买通了船员 所有人
Sakharine!
萨卡林
Nobody takes my ship!
没有人可以夺走我的船
You're the captain?
你就是船长?
Of course I'm the captain. Who else could I be?
除了我还能是谁
I've been locked in this room for days
我被锁在这里好多天了
with only whisky to sustain my mortal soul.
只有威士忌能能慰藉我的灵魂
Well, I assumed it was locked.
我以为是锁着的
Well, it's not.
没有锁
Now, you must excuse me. If they find me here, they'll kill me.
我得走了 他们抓到我 会杀了我的
I have to keep moving. Try and find my way off this drunken tub.
我得不停移动 离开这个酒坛子
"Tub"? Tub?
坛子?
Tub?
坛子!
- Thanks. - Pleasure.
- 谢谢 - 接着他
I'm Tintin, by the way.
对了 我叫丁丁
Haddock. Archibald Haddock.
阿道克 阿奇博尔德・阿道克
There's a longboat up on deck. Follow me.
欢迎登船 跟我来
Hang on a second.
等等
Did you say "Haddock"?
你是说阿道克
How could you let them escape?
你们怎么能放跑他们
Find them. Find them both.
去找 抓到他们
- Don't worry, we'll kill them, sir. - No.
- 别担心 我们会杀了他们的 - 不
You can kill the boy. Not Haddock.
可以杀那孩子 阿道克不能杀
What? He's just a hopeless old soak.
他就是个没救的老酒鬼
We should've killed him long since.
早就该杀掉他了
You think it's an accident that I chose Haddock's ship, Haddock's crew,
你以为我是无意选中阿道克的船吗 阿道克的船员
Haddock's treacherous first mate?
阿道克不可靠的大副
Nothing is an accident.
没有什么是意外的
We go back a long way, Captain Haddock and I.
我和阿道克船长的交情可长着呢
We've unfinished business.
我们俩还没完呢
And this time, I'm going to make him pay.
这次我要让他付出代价
We have to reach a locked door at the end of this corridor. This is gonna be tricky.
我们要去走廊尽头 一间锁着的房间 这会很不容易
You wouldn't happen to be related
你该不会和马林斯派克大厅的
to the Haddocks of Marlinspike Hall, would you?
阿道克家族有关系吧?
Why do you ask?
问这干嘛?
It's for a story I've been working on.
我在写一个故事
An old shipwreck that happened off the coast of Barbados.
关于一艘从巴巴多斯离岸的失事船只
A man o'war. Triple masted. Fifty guns.
是艘战舰配有50门炮的三桅船
What do you know of the Unicorn?
关于独角兽号 你都知道些什么
Not a lot. That's why I'm asking you.
不太多 所以我才问你
The secret of that ship is known only to my family!
那艘船的秘密只有我的家族知道
It's been passed down from generation to generation.
代代相传
My granddaddy himself, with his dying breath, told me the tale.
我祖父临死前告诉我 他们全都...
And?
然后呢
Gone.
没了
What do you mean, gone?
没了是什么意思
I was so upset when he kicked the bucket, I had no choice but to drown my sorrows.
他踢水桶时时 我很生气 只好借酒浇愁
When I woke up in the morning, it was gone! I'd forgotten it all.
第二天早上我醒来时 什么都不记得了
- Everything? - Every last word.
- 什么都不记得? - 一个字都不记得
Well, is there somebody else in your family? Maybe they would know.
你家还有什么人吗?也许他们记得
Sir Francis had three sons. All but my bloodline failed.
弗朗西斯有三个儿子 除了我这支血脉 别的都死了
I am the last of the Haddocks!
我是阿道克家族最后一个人了
Did you say three sons?
你刚说有三个儿子?
Let's check below!
检查下面
There is a bottle of rum for the man who finds Haddock.
有一个喝着朗姆酒人发现鳕鱼的瓶子
And kill the boy. Hope I find him first.
并杀死男孩 希望我先找到他
What's that?
什么声音?
You're hearing things.
你听到了
Quiet, Ali.
安静
There's nothing there.
什么都没有
Let's go UP...
走 我们上去
I know what Sakharine's looking for.
我知道萨卡林在找什么了
- What are you raving on about? - It was written on the scroll.
- 你在嘀咕什么? - 纸卷上写的是
"Three brothers joined."
三兄弟一同驾驶
"Three Unicorns in company sailing in the noonday sun will speak."
三艘独角兽号 航行在正午时分 太阳会告诉你
Really?
真的?
Sir Francis didn't make two models of the Unicorn.
弗朗西斯不是造了两个独角兽号模型
He made three!
他造了三艘
Three ships for three sons.
三个儿子各一艘
Excellent!
厉害
Sakharine's after the third model ship.
萨卡林在找第三艘模型
Barnacles! Someone's locked the door!
该死 门被锁上了
- Well, is there a key? - A key?
- 有钥匙吗? - 钥匙?
Yes, now, that would be the problem.
问题就在这儿
Mr Jaggerman!
加格曼
Top bunk in the centre. Keeper of the keys.
睡在上铺的 看管着钥匙
Careful, mind. He's a restless sleeper on account of the tragic loss of his eyelids.
小心点 他几乎不睡觉的 他在一场悲剧中输了眼睛
- He lost his eyelids? - Aye.
- 他输了眼球? - 是啊
Now, that was a card game to remember.
不堪回首的纸牌游戏
You really had to be there.
你得过去
I'd do this myself, Tintin,
我本可以自己去
but you've a lighter tread and less chance of waking the boys.
但你更不容易惊醒人
- Are you sure this is a good idea? - You've nothing to worry about.
- 你确定这是个好主意吗 - 你不用担心
Provided they all stay asleep.
何况他们都烂醉如泥
I wouldn't get too close to Mr Hobbs.
我是不会太靠近霍布斯
He's very handy with a razor.
他的剃刀耍的可厉害了
And I'd steer clear of Mr Gitch.
还有别碰到 格里奇
Sacked as a shepherd on account of his "animal husbandry."
他之前因在船上养宠物 被解雇了
Not the sandwich.
别拿三明治
The keys!
拿钥匙
You're a brave lad, Tintin.
你真勇敢 丁丁
My heart was in my mouth, I don't mind telling you.
不怕跟你说 我心都提到嗓子眼了
Well, that is, if it was my heart.
好吧 如果那是我的心的话
Judging by my stomach, it could've been anything, really.
从胃里翻出来的东西 什么都有可能
Hurry up, Captain! We've no time to lose.
快点 船长 没时间可浪费了
Bingo!
好了
Just the necessities, of course.
都是些必需品
To the lifeboats.
去救生艇
Ease it in!
眼睛擦亮点
Put your back into it!
转过身去
Hold her there, steady!
稳住她 镇定
Any sign of him, Jumbo?
- 发现他了吗?
- Nothing yet. - Watch yourself. The boss says he's a handful.
- 还没 - 留神 老板说他不好对付
Come on.
走了
It's Allan.
是阿伦
- Is that the bridge? - Aye, on the other side of the radio room.
- 舰桥上那个? - 对 另一边就是无线电室
Radio room?
无线电室
Wait here, Captain. Sound the alarm if anyone comes.
在这儿等着 船长 有人靠近就发警报
Careful, Tintin.
小心点 丁丁
I can't see a thing!
我看不到东西
Quit your whining and find the kid!
别抱怨了 赶紧找到孩子
I didn't sign on for this!
我没有签这个
Keep searching!
继续找
- Message just come through, boss. - What's it say?
- 老板刚下了命令 - 说什么?
"The Milanese Nightingale has landed. Waiting in the wings for action."
"米兰夜莺已着陆 只待信号 便可展翅"
"Milanese Nightingale"?
米兰夜莺
Now pray this cheers him up.
希望这个能让他高兴
"Bagghar"
巴格赫港
What's this?
这是什么?
"The Sultanate of Bagghar"
巴格赫的领地
"ruled over by Sheikh Omar Ben Salaad,"
被奥马尔・本・塞兰德统治着
"whose love of music and culture is matched only by his love of..."
他对音乐和文化的热爱只有
Great snakes!
天呐
Bagghar.
巴格赫港
The Port of Bagghar.
Morocco.
在摩洛哥
Tintin!
丁丁
Hey! Put your hands up!
嘿 举起手来
And let that be a lesson to you!
这下给你上一课
Help me!
救命
In here! He's in here!
这儿 在这儿
Here! By the lifeboats!
这里 救生艇旁边
Out of the way!
走开!
After him! Get him!
去追他!捉住他!
Quick, quick, in here!
快 快 这里!
Over there!
这边
Why, you little...
你小子...
- He's up there! - Go!
- 他在上边 - 快
I can see him now!
我看见他了
Don't let them get away!
别让他们跑了!
Help me!
救我!
- Turn this ship around! - Aye, sir!
- 掉头 - 是长官
Get me a flare!
把火炬给我
Captain, get down! Get down!
船长 趴下 趴下!
- There he is! - Get out of the way!
- 他在那儿 - 让开
Now! Full ahead! Full speed!
在前面 全速前进
Got you now.
发现你了
Stay down.
趴低
Look! Down there!
看下边
Idiots! You idiots! What have you done?
白痴 你都干了什么
We killed them, boss, like you wanted!
我们杀了他们 照你说的
No! Not like I wanted! I needed Haddock alive!
不 我不要这样 我要阿道克活着
Wait a minute, boss! There are two boats missing!
等等 老板 有两艘船不见了
So, that one must have been a decoy.
没错 那艘船一定是圈套
They're onto us, and our destination.
他们知道我们的计划和目的地
Find them! Make absolutely certain they never reach Bagghar!
找到他们 确保他们到不了 巴格赫港
Yes, boss.
是 头儿
Get up there!
起来
We have to get to Bagghar ahead of Sakharine.
我们必须在萨克林前到达巴格赫港
I know. I know.
我知道 我知道
Why?
为什么?
Because he has the third model ship.
因为他有第三艘模型
How do you know?
你怎么知道?
The Sheikh collects old ships.
谢赫收藏旧船
And this is the prize of his collection.
这是他收藏品的标价
Blistering blue barnacles, that is the Unicorn!
臭贝壳是独角兽号
Captain, do you see the distortion around the model?
船长 你看到模型边缘有点失真吗
Aye.
看到了
It means that Ben Salaad exhibits it in a bulletproof glass case in his palace.
意味着本・塞兰德在他宫殿里 设了个防弹玻璃罩
And Sakharine is going there to steal it!
萨克林要去偷
Yes, he has a secret weapon. The Milanese Nightingale.
他有秘密武器 就是米兰夜莺
But that won't be enough to solve the mystery,
但这还不够揭开秘密
and that is why Sakharine needs you.
所以 萨克林需要你
That's why he made you his prisoner.
所以他囚禁了你
There is something he needs you to remember.
他需要你想起些什么
I don't follow you.
我听不懂
I read it in a book.
我在一本书上看过
That only a true Haddock can discover the secret of the Unicorn.
真正的阿道克后人 才能解开独角兽号的秘密
I don't remember anything about anything.
我什么都不记得
But you must know about your ancestors, Sir Francis. It's your family legacy!
但你一定记得你的祖先弗朗西斯 这可是你家的遗产
My memory is not what it used to be.
我脑子可不如以前好使了
- Well, what did it used to be? - I've forgotten.
- 以前什么样子 - 我忘了
Captain,
船长
can you get us to Bagghar?
你能带我们去巴格赫港吗?
What sort of a stupid question is that?
这算什么蠢问题
Give me those oars! I'll show you some real seamanship, laddie.
给我桨 让你们见识见识真正的航海驾驶技术
I'll not be doubted by some pipsqueak tuft of ginger and his irritating dog!
我不会让一个乳臭未干的小子 和他恼人的狗质疑
I am master and commander of the seas!
我是海洋的主人和指挥官
I know these waters better than the warts on my mother's face!
我对这片海的了解超过我妈脸上的瘤子
Look at the pair of them. Fast asleep.
看这俩家伙 这么快就睡着了
Typical landlubbers. Aye, no stamina these days.
典型的旱鸭子 挨不过这些天了
Never mind. I'll get you there, Tintin.
别担心 我会带你去的 丁丁
Look, Thomson. There's the fellow.
看 汤姆森 就是那家伙
Oh, my.
哦 天呐
- Mr Silk? - Yes?
- 希尔克先生 - 我是
- My name is Thompson. - And Thomson.
- 我叫汤普森 - 我是汤姆森
- We're police officers! - We're police officers!
- 我们是警察 - 我们是警察
Oh, crumbs.
哦 要命
Good gracious!
真惨
- Mr Silk! - Mr Silk!
- 希尔克先生 - 希尔克先生
- Dear, oh, dear, oh, dear. - Are you okay?
- 天啊 哦 天啊 哦 天啊 - 你还好吗?
Poor fellow!
可怜的家伙
- Are you all right? - Are you all right, sir?
- 你还好吗 先生 - 你还好吗 先生
- Here, let me help you up. - Thank you, that's very kind.
- 我来帮你 - 谢谢 没事
- No need to run away, sir. - No, no, you see,
- 没必要跑 - 是这样的
yesterday we very nearly caught the pickpocket who's been terrorizing the town!
昨天 我们差点抓到一个在城里四处行窃的扒手
Pickpocket?
扒手?
We pulled his jacket off and inside we found a wallet.
我们扯掉了他的外套然后发现了一个钱包
A wallet with your name and address!
一个写有你名字和地址的钱包
- That's my wallet. - Well, it's obvious he stole it from you.
- 这是我的钱包 - 很明显是他从你那儿偷的
- No, no, that's my wallet. - Are you all right, sir?
- 没错 是我的 - 你还好吗 先生
We didn't mean to startle you. Let us help you into your apartment.
我们不是有意吓到你的 我们送你回家吧
Thank you so much. No need to come in. I'll be quite all right, really.
谢谢你们 不用进来了 我一会就没事了
- No, we insist. - Better safe than sorry.
- 不 我们坚持 - 安全总好过对不起
- It's the least we can do. - Thank you.
- 起码我们还能做到这些 - 哦 谢谢你
There we are.
好了
Good grief! What's all this?
天呐 这些都是什么
It's my collection?
是我的收藏品
- What a lot of wallets! - I can't help it.
- 这钱包可真不少啊 - 我克制不了
It started with coin purses and sort of went on from there, really.
开始只是硬币包 然后就一发不可收拾
You want to be careful. Haven't you heard? There's a pickpocket about.
你可要小心了 听说过吗?这附近有个扒手
- Yes, he'd love this. Can you imagine? - What do you mean, "pickpocket"?
- 对 你能想象吗? - 你说什么扒手
A master criminal.
一个犯罪大师
A bag-snatching, purse-pilfering, wallet-lifting sneak thief!
偷个包包 顺个钱包的钱包大盗
I'm not a bad person.
我不是坏人
I'm a kleptomaniac.
只是有这个癖好
- A what? - It's a fear of open spaces.
- 什么 - 就是害怕公开场所
Poor man. No wonder he keeps his wallets in the living room.
难怪他把钱包都放在起居室
Wallets. I just can't resist the lovely little things.
钱包 我就是抗拒不了这些小玩意
It's a harmless little habit, really.
这是种无害的小癖好
Good heavens, Thomson, look at this! His name's Thompson, too.
看这个 他也叫汤姆森
What a coincidence.
真巧
No, Thomson, this is Thomson without a as in "psychic."
- 不对 汤普森 这个汤姆森不带“P”
No, no, no, it's Thompson with a as in "psychologist."
不 不 这个汤普森带P
Look at this one! A green one that I managed to pick
看这个绿色的 我就是从它开始
from a pickpocket actually pickpocketing at the time.
踏上收藏钱包之路的
- And this one! Cuir de cochon. - No, you have it all wrong.
- 还有这个 - 你个文盲字都不认识
- There is a "P" in "psychic." - I am not your sidekick! You are mine!
- “精神”里面有一个“P” - 我不是你的伙伴 你是我的
- Smell it, won't you? Piggy leather! - No, you have it all wrong.
- 闻一下 没闻到吗?小猪皮革 - 不 你完全错了
- How dare you! - How dare you!
- 你敢这么说? - 你敢这么说?
- I met you first. - I met you first.
- 是你先挑起来的 - 你先挑起来的
- No, you didn't. - Yes, I did.
- 是你 - 不 是你
- No, you did not. - Yes, I did.
- Didn't! - Did!
-是你 - 是你
- Listen! I can't stand it any more! - Hey!
- 住口!我再也受不了 - 嗨
All right, I'll come quietly.
我受够了 我投降
Take them! Take them! Take them all!
拿走 把它们都拿走吧
Stop it. Pull yourself together, man!
好了 你疯了吗?
We can't take your wallets! Do we look like thieves?
我们才不拿走你的钱包呢 那不成窃贼了嘛?
Good heavens, Thompson.
上帝啊 杜邦
This looks familiar.
这个太眼熟了
Can't be.
不会吧
It is!
是丁丁的
- Tintin! - Tintin!
- 丁丁 - 丁丁
I'm so cold.
真冷啊
And thirsty.
又渴的厉害
My throat is parched.
喉咙太难受了
Let's see if there's any fresh water.
我记得这里有水和干粮的
What have we here?
啊哈...看我找到了什么?
Tintin.
丁丁
Come and warm yourself, laddie.
过来暖和一下身子 小伙子
Captain?
船长
- What have you done? - No need to thank me.
- 你都做了什么? - 没必要感谢我
What?
什么?
Well, you looked a little cold, so I lit a wee fire.
你看起来受了点凉 所以我生了堆火
In a boat?
在船里?
No! Those are our oars! We need those oars!
不 那可是我们的桨我们需要它们
Yes, but not for much longer.
是的 但很快就不需要了
Have you gone mad? Quick, Captain, help me!
你疯了?快点 船长 帮帮我!
- Captain, help me, quick! - He's right. What have I done?
- 船长 帮我 快点! - 哦 我都做了什么?
- What have I done? - No, Captain, not that!
- 我都做了什么? - 不 船长 那个不行
Thundering typhoons!
雷鸣般的台风
Well, this is a fine mess.
真是一团糟啊我们被困在这了
- I'm weak. - We're stranded here...
- 我懦弱 - 我们滞留在这里...
- Selfish. - ...with no hope of rescue...
- 自私 - ...没有救援的希望......
I'm hopeless.
没希望得救了
While Sakharine and his men are halfway to Bagghar.
现在他的人已经在去 巴格赫港的路上了
Poor, miserable wretch!
- 可怜的 可悲的混蛋!
Yes, all right. That's enough of that.
行了 够了 别抱怨了
It was his fault, you see. It was Sir Francis.
你看 这是他的错弗朗西斯爵士的错
Tell me, how did you work that one out?
告诉我 你是怎么得出这个结论的?
Because he was a figurehead of great courage and bold exploits.
因为他曾经是英勇无畏探险的标志!
No one like him ever existed in my family.
像他那样的人之前 我们家族里从来没有过
Why do you think I drink?
你认为喝酒好么
Because I know I'll never be like him.
因为我知道 我永远不会像他那样
No, it's far better that I end it now. Put us both out of our misery.
不会 最好我现在做个了结 从这不幸中得到解脱
What is it, Snowy?
那是什么 白雪?
I'm gonna lower myself into the sea.
我要往下沉一沉
Into the cold embrace of the big blue!
投入这冰冷深蓝的拥抱
Those are Portuguese markings.
这些是葡萄牙人的标记
- Are you even listening? - Where is the Karaboudjan registered?
- 你听见了吗? - 卡拉布让号是在那注册的
We're saved.
我们得救了
We're saved!
得救了!
It's a sign from above!
我们得救了!
- Troglodytes! - Captain, get down.
- 穴居人! - 船长 趴下
Slave-traders! Mutant malingerers!
二道贩子!变异病鬼!
Freshwater politicians!
菜鸟!
Bad news, Captain. We've only got one bullet.
坏消息 船长 我们只有一发子弹了
- And what's the good news? - We've got one bullet.
- 好消息呢? - 我们还有一发子弹
You got him!
成了!
Well done, my boy.
啊!做的好 小兄弟
Stay here, Captain.
呆在这里 船长
Tintin?
丁丁!
- Don't take your eyes off of them. - Hurry up!
- 看好他们! - 快
Just as I thought. The ignition lead has been cut.
正如我所料 点火线都被打断了!
Lucky shot!
啊!真够走运的!
One more pass, and we will finish them off.
再飞回来一次我们就能结果了他们
Put your hands in the air.
举起手来
Now!
马上!
Let's see here.
让我想想
You do know what you're doing, eh, Tintin?
你知道你在做什么吗?丁丁?
More or less.
差不多吧
Well, which is it? More or less?
那到底差多少?
Relax. I interviewed a pilot once.
放松点 我曾经采访过一个飞行员
Which way to North Africa?
去北非怎么走?
Captain, look!
船长 看
We've caught up with them.
我们追上了他们了
Wonderful!
真赞!
But you think we might find another way to North Africa
但你觉得我们有希望找另一条路去北非么?
that doesn't take us through that Wall of Death?
我们可过不了那死亡之墙
We can't turn back.
我们无路可退了
Not now.
现在不行
现在不行!
No, Captain! Those are surgical spirits for medicinal purposes only.
不 船长!那些外科酒精只能医用
Quite right, laddie, quite right.
没错 小兄弟 没错
No, no, no!
不 不 不!
The fuel tank! It's almost empty!
油箱快空了
Captain! This may sound crazy, but I've got a plan.
船长 我有个计划 但听起来有点疯狂
The alcohol in that bottle may give us a few more miles.
这瓶酒精应该能让我们再飞几英里
I need you to climb out of the plane and pour it into the fuel tank.
我需要你爬到飞机外面然后把这些倒进油箱
Christopher Columbus!
克里斯多弗・哥伦布!
There's a terrible storm out there.
外面暴风真猛
And it's raining.
还下着雨
And you call yourself a Haddock?
你不是说自己是阿道克家族的么?
Captain!
船长?
Captain! Can you hear me?
船长 能听见么?
Captain!
船长!
Captain?
船长?
You're doing fine! Now, pour the bottle into the tank.
你做的真棒 现在把酒精倒进油箱里
We're running on fumes.
冒烟了!
Fumes!
烟!
Oh, no.
哦 不
Captain! I can't see!
船长!我看不见了!
Land! Land!
陆地!陆地!
We can't! We're not there yet!
不能着陆 我们还没到呢!
No, land!
不是着陆
No, no, no, starboard! Starboard! Starboard!
不 不 不 向右 向右 向右!
Hang on, Tintin!
坚持住 丁丁!
I'm coming!
我来了!
The Land of Thirst.
没水的陆地
没水的陆地!
- The Land of Thirst. - Will you stop saying that?
- 没水的陆地! - 你能不能不说了!
You don't understand. I've run out.
你不懂 我们没水了
I've run out. You don't know what that means.
你还真不知道这意味着什么
Captain, we have to keep going.
船长 我们得继续走
One step at a time. Come on, on your feet! Lean your weight on me.
一步一步来加油 用脚走倚在我身上
A man can only hang on so long without his vitals.
没了命根 我也就到这了
Captain, calm down. There are worse things than sobering up.
船长 冷静点 这比让你酒醒更糟糕
Look! Tintin!
看 丁丁!
We're saved.
我们有救了!
Water. Water!
水!水!
Stop! Captain!
停下 船长
It's just a mirage!
那只是海市蜃楼
But it was here. I saw it.
刚才确实在的 我看到了
It was just your mind playing tricks. It's the heat!
那只是你脑袋里臆想出来的因为太热了
I have to go home.
我得回家了
- What? - I have to go back to the sea.
- 什么? - 我得回到海上
Captain, you're hallucinating.
船长 你出现幻觉了
Look.
看那
Did you ever see a more beautiful sight?
你们看到过比这更美丽的东西么?
She's turning into the wind, all sails set.
她随风而去船全准备好了
Triple masted.
三桅
Double decks. Fifty guns.
双甲板 50门炮
The Unicorn?
独角兽号?
- Isn't she a beauty? - Yes! Yes, she is!
- 她是不是个美人? - 是的没错
Tell me, Captain, what else can you see?
跟我说说 船长 你还看见了什么?
She's got the wind behind her.
此船乘风破浪
Look at the pace she's setting!
四平八稳
Barely a day out of Barbados,
仅仅是巴巴多斯很平常的一天
a hold full of rum and the finest tobacco
满载着朗姆酒 上好的雪茄
and the hearts of the sailors set for home.
和水手们的似箭归心
The red pennant.
红色警报
The blood runs cold in every sea captain who looks upon that flag,
船长看着信号旗 平静下来
for he knows he's facing a fight to the death.
因为他们知道他们将会决一死战
But Sir Francis is a Haddock.
但弗朗西斯爵士是阿道克家族的人
And Haddocks don't flee.
阿道克家族的人是不会临阵脱逃的
All hands on deck! Gunners to their stations!
全员甲板集合!枪手就位!
Let's unload the King's shot into these
我们来给这些
yellow-bellied, lily-livered sea slugs!
胆小的黄胖子海盗点颜色看看
- Prepare to bring her about, Mr Nicholls. - Aye-aye, Captain!
- 准备调转船头!尼克尔斯 - 好的 船长
Prepare to bring her about!
准备调转船头!
Fire!
开火!
Portside gun, fire!
左舷炮 开火!
Look lively, lads!
喜欢吧 伙计们!
- Mr Nicholls, secure the cargo. - Right you are, sir.
- 尼克尔斯 去保护货仓 - 马上去 长官
Prepare to repel all boarders!
准备击退登船的敌人!
This way! We need more men!
上啊 我们需要更多人手
And then he saw him.
后来他 看到他了
Like a phantom, rising from the dead.
像幽灵一样从死尸中出来!
Who?
谁
Captain, who did he see?
船长 你看到了谁?
It's gone.
船消失了
What do you mean, gone? What happened next?
消失了是什么意思?接下来发生了什么?
By Jupiter, I have a beard! Since when did I have a beard?
噢 丘比特 我长了胡子 我什么时候长的?
Captain, something happened on the Unicorn.
船长 独角兽号上肯定发生了什么
It's the key to everything. You must try to remember.
这是所有事情的关键 你必须努力想起来
The Unicorn? What? I'm so terribly thirsty.
独角兽号?什么?渴死我了
- Captain! - Tintin!
- 船长! - 丁丁
What is happening to me?
我怎么了?
And to think all it took was a day in the Sahara.
回忆起这些 在撒哈拉沙漠只需要一天时间
Congratulations, Captain, you're sober.
恭喜你 船长 你酒醒了
Sober.
醒了
Good dog!
宝贝儿 你真棒
This one's alive.
这个还活着
- Check the other! - Yes, sir.
- 看下另一个 - 是 长官!
I'm Lieutenant Delcourt. Welcome to the Afghar Outpost.
我是戴乐古中尉 欢迎来到阿付伽前哨
Thank you, Lieutenant. We owe you our lives.
感谢你 中尉 你救了我们一命
- Did you find my friend? - Yes, but he's not in good shape, I'm afraid.
- 你找到我的朋友了么? - 找到了 但恐怕他情况不太好
He's still suffering the effects of acute dehydration. He's quite delirious.
脱水令他很难受 他有点精神错乱
Why don't we pay him a visit?
为什么我们不去看看他呢
Haddock! You're awake.
噢 阿道克 你醒了
Good! I have a visitor for you.
很好 有个人要见你
- Captain? - Hello!
- 船长 - 你好
I think you've got the wrong room.
我想你走错房间了
Captain, it's Tintin.
船长 我是丁丁
Our plane crashed in the desert. Don't you remember?
我们的飞机在沙漠坠机了 你难道不记得了?
Plane? No, no, I'm a naval man myself. I never fly if I can help it.
飞机?噢不 我可是海兵 我从没坐过飞机
He's got me confused with someone else.
他看来是认错人了
What is this peculiar liquid?
这奇怪的液体是什么?
There's no bouquet. It's completely transparent.
没味道 完全透明的
Why, it's water.
啊 那是水
What will they think of next?
他们接下来会怎么想?
We suspect he has a concussion. Heatstroke. Delirium.
嗯 我们怀疑他脑震荡了 中暑了 胡言乱语
He's sober.
他酒醒了!
Now, Captain, out in the desert...
嗯 船长 当我们在沙漠的时候
- The desert? - Yes. You were talking about Sir Francis.
- 沙漠? - 是的 你当时在说弗朗西斯爵士
- Sir who? - Sir Francis.
- 什么爵士?- 弗朗西斯爵士
And you were telling me about what happened on the Unicorn.
你当时正跟我说独角兽号上发生的事...
- The unicorn! - Yes!
- 独角兽! - 是的
The stuff that dreams are made of.
啊 那是在儿时的梦里
Wee children's dreams.
出现的东西
No, the ship. Please try to remember, Captain.
不 是船 请仔细想想 船长
Lives are at risk.
命垂一线
Snowy, what have you done?
白雪 你都做了什么?
I'd stand back if I were you.
如果我是你 我会马上闪人
Out! Everybody out of the room!
他要发作了 所有人都出去!
Snowy!
白雪!
This man is insane!
这家伙疯了
Show yourself, Red Rackham!
出来 红色拉克姆
If it's a fight you want, you've met your match!
如果这是你要的决斗 你遇到对手了!
A fight With Who?
跟谁决斗?
To the death, Red Rackham!
决一死战 红色拉克姆
No, wait!
不 等等
Wait. Captain...
等等 船长
I remember everything now.
我都想起来了
Everything Granddaddy told me.
我爷爷跟我讲的所有事
The Unicorn was taken.
独角兽号被抢走了
The pirates were now masters of the ship.
海盗占领了船
The crew surrendered?
船员投降了?
Granddaddy said that Red Rackham called Sir Francis the King's dog.
爷爷说红色拉克姆叫弗朗西斯爵士 是国王的走狗
A pirate hunter sent to reclaim their hard-won plunder.
一个为他们的疯狂掠夺 而派出的海盗猎手
Why would I waste my time on rum, tobacco, molasses and dates
为何我去喝酒、抽雪茄、品糖浆 泡妹子来浪费时间
when you have a more valuable cargo on board?
而不来抢你船上这些价值连城宝藏呢?
Where is it?
藏哪了?
You'll have to kill me first.
你还是先杀了我吧
Not first, no.
不先杀你 不
Please.
求你
I'll start with your men.
我要先拿你的船员们开刀
To save his men,
为了救他的船员
he would give up the secret cargo.
他放弃了秘藏的宝藏
And where was it?
宝藏藏哪了?
Four hundredweight of gold, jewels and treasure.
400磅的黄金、首饰和珍宝
Kill his men!
把他们推到海里去!
No, Rackham! No!
不!拉克姆 不!
Rackham, you gave me your word! Rackham!
你承诺过的拉克姆 拉克姆!
Rackham!
拉克姆!
Sir Francis knew he was doomed.
弗朗西斯爵士知道他已经完了
That he'd be hung from the highest yardarm.
他被吊在最高的横杆上
But they didn't reckon on one thing!
但有一件事他们没想到
Sir Francis was a Haddock.
弗朗西斯爵士是阿道克人
And a Haddock always has a trick up his sleeve.
阿道克人总会留一手
And with that, he hurls himself forward!
他就这样又冲上去了!
On the pirates? Like that? Unarmed?
面对那群海盗 像那样没有武装?
No! No, on a bottle of rum rolling on the deck.
没有 他看到一瓶朗姆酒在甲板上
And he opens it up, and puts it to his lips, and...
并打开了它 然后他把瓶子放到嘴边
And then he stops.
然后他停下了
"This is no time for drinking," he says. "I need all my wits about me."
没时间喝酒了 他说 我得想想办法
With that, he puts down the bottle and...
他放下了酒瓶
Yes, yes, he puts down the bottle...
是是 是的 他放下了酒瓶
And he seizes a cutlass.
拿起了剑
And then he makes his way to the ship's magazine,
他杀到了船上的弹药库
where they keep all the gunpowder and the shot!
在那储存着所有火药和枪支
YOU dog!
你这家伙
You'd blow us sky high?
你想把我们都炸到天上去吗?
Come on, then.
好吧 来啊
Let's have you.
我先把你解决掉
Not this time.
这次没戏
You!
你!
Captain, what is it?
船长 怎么了?
How could I be so blind?
我怎么这么盲目呢?
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
This isn't just about the scrolls or.
这不仅仅是些纸卷...
Or the treasure that went down with the ship.
宝藏和船一起沉到了海底...
It's me.
是我!
It's me he's after!
他在追缉我!
You'll suffer a curse upon you and your name, Haddock.
你和你的家族都会被诅咒的 阿道克
He wants vengeance.
他想要复仇
Come back and face me!
回过头来看着我!
- Hurry, Tintin. - What?
- 快 丁丁 - 什么?
- We're out of time. - Captain!
- 我们没时间了 - 船长!
I curse you!
诅咒你
I curse your name and all who come after!
诅咒你的家族和你所有的后裔!
We will meet again, Haddock!
我们还会再见的 阿道克!
In another time! In another life!
在另一个时代!另一个世界
It's not over. It was never over!
这还没有结束 永远不会结束
I don't understand. Who's after your blood?
我不明白 谁在追你?
- Sakharine! - Sakharine? Why?
- 萨哈林 - 萨哈林?为什么?
He's Red Rackham's descendent! He means to finish it!
他是红色拉克姆的后裔 他要做个了结
- That's why he did it. - Did what?
- 这就是他为什么这么干 - 怎么干?
Sank his own ship. Sir Francis sent that treasure to the bottom of the sea.
把自己的船弄沉!弗朗西斯爵士把宝藏沉入了海底
He would be damned before he let Red Rackham have it.
在红色拉克姆得到宝藏前 他会被诅咒
- And he was. - But he couldn't let it lie.
- 确实是 - 但他不能弃之而去
- No. - He left a clue.
- 没错 -他留下了线索
Three clues wrapped in a riddle, concealing a secret.
三条包含在暗语中的线索 隐藏着这个秘密
But only a true Haddock would be able to solve it.
但只有真正的阿道克人能解出它
- What secret? - The location.
- 一个秘密? - 沉船位置
To one of the greatest sunken treasures in all history.
史上价值最高的沉船位置之一
The wreck of the Unicorn.
独角兽号的残骸
He means to steal it! The third scroll!
他是有意的来偷这第三张纸卷!
Billions of blue, blistering barnacles!
该死的臭藤壶!
I swear, as the last of the Haddocks, I'll find that treasure before him!
作为阿道克家族最后的后裔 我一定比他先找到宝藏
To Bagghar.
去巴格赫港
He's here.
他在这
It's no good. They could be anywhere.
这不行 它可能在任何地方
Captain.
船长
Don't look now, but we're being followed.
别回头 我们已经被跟踪了
Yes, we are.
啊 确实是啊
What do you want? Why are you following us?
你们想干什么?为什么跟踪我们?
Who are you working for?
你们在等谁?
Captain, stop! Stop!
船长 住手!住手!
- Thompson and Thomson. - Not so loud.
- 汤普森和汤姆森 - 别这么大声
- We're in disguise. - So I see.
- 我们正伪装着呢 - 噢 我明白了
You got the message I sent from the ship?
你们收到我从船上发的消息了么?
Yes, well, bit of a long story, that.
是的 呃 说来话长啊
The upshot is we caught the thief, retrieved your wallet,
简单说就是 我们抓到那个贼找回你的钱包
and then hopped on the next plane to Bagghar.
然后跳上下一班飞机到了巴格赫港
Yes, that pocket picker has picked his last pocket.
是的 那个扒手的最后一次了
There. Don't worry. He didn't take any money.
别担心 钱一分没少
It's not the money I'm worried about.
我担心的并不是钱
The odds are even.
鹿死谁手 尚未知晓
Now, to find the next two scrolls.
现在 我们需要找到另外两个纸卷
The Milanese Nightingale.
米兰夜莺
That's his secret weapon?
那是他的秘密武器
What a dish.
哇塞!秀色可餐啊
Enchanted, signora!
令人着迷的
Benvenuto! Welcome! Marhaba!
宾奉托夫人 欢迎您!
We are blessed with your presence.
您的到来让我们深感荣幸
Yes. Indeed, Signor Salad!
是的 当然 塞兰德先生
What charming peasants.
多友好的村民们啊!
May I introduce my escort,
请让我来介绍一下我的护花使者
Monsieur Shuggair Addeitiff.
修格・阿德提夫 先生
He's been very
他一直很
passionate in his support of this concert.
热情的支持这场音乐会
It's my first visit to the Third World.
这是我第一次到第三世界来
Please forgive me. I must escort madame to her dressing room. Excuse us.
请原谅 我得陪这位女士去换衣间了不好意思
After you.
女士优先
(NEV-R-BREAK牌防弹玻璃)
- Hello, how are you? - Hello...
- 嗨 最近怎么样? - 嗨
Here. I want you to look after this.
给 我想让你来保管这个你干什么呢?
- What are you doing? - Me?
- 你要干什么? - 我?
- Yes. - Are you sure?
- 是啊 - 你确定么?
If I'm caught, I don't want them to find this on me.
如果我被抓的话 我不想让他们把这个从我这翻出来
Look, just keep it hidden.
保管好它
I will guard this with my life!
我会用生命来保护它
Get up! Get up!
快起来!
It's her!
是她
Blistering barnacles!
臭藤壶
What's that noise?
这是什么声音?
My ears,
我的耳朵
- they're bleeding. - No, they're not.
- 在流血 - 没流血
Captain.
船长!
Shut up, Snowy.
别吵 白雪
Oh, Columbus, it's every man for himself! Make way.
噢 天啊!我实在是受不了了!
Make way! Medical emergency.
借光 借光!请照顾下病号!
That was close.
好险啊
Hello, Captain.
你好啊 船长
You!
是你!
Oh, no!
噢 不
Sakharine!
萨哈林
The falcon! Snowy, after him!
那只鹰!白雪 跟上它!
Tintin! Tintin!
丁丁!丁丁!
Those two! There! They're here to steal your ship!
那边那两个人 他们要偷你的船!
No, no, no, no, no, we're not!
不 不 我们没有!
Arrest him! The ugly one!
逮捕他 还有那个丑家伙!
- No, wait! - Who, me?
- 不 等下! - 谁?我?
Yes!
对!
Thief! Arrest him!
那个贼!逮捕他!
Captain!
船长!
- Sakharine's got the scroll! - It's worse than that.
- 萨哈林拿到了那个纸卷 - 还有更糟糕的
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
They took your scroll, Tintin. It's gone.
他们也拿到了你的纸卷 弄丢了
How? What happened?
怎么丢的?发生了什么事?
It was Allan.
是阿伦干的
He knobbled me in the garden, and then
他在花园里把我打晕 然后
- there was a bottle of alcohol and... - There always is.
- 有瓶酒... - 总是这样
No, no! No, not like that.
不 不 不是那样的
I can smell it on you.
我能从你身上闻出酒味
Hurry. Back to the boat.
快点 回船上
- Tintin! Where are you going? - I'm going after Sakharine.
- 丁丁 你要去哪? - 去追萨哈林
- By yourself? - Yes?
- 你自己? - 是的
Come on, Snowy!
来啊 白雪
Catch them, catch them!
抓住他们!抓住他们!
Lose them! Get him off our tail!
甩开他们!别让他们跟着我们!
Did you hit anything?
你打中什么了吗?
Oh, dear.
噢 天啊
Faster, you idiot, faster!
快点 你个白痴
Not again!
再快点
- I'll have those, thank you. - Come on, Snowy!
- 我来拿着吧 谢谢啊 - 快点 白雪!
No!
不!
Incoming falcon at four o'clock!
4点钟方向有鹰来袭!
Tintin, faster!
丁丁 再快点!
- The scrolls! - I got one, two...
- 纸卷? - 接住了 一个两个!
And three!
三个!
Snowy!
白雪!
Oh, no! Not again.
噢不!别再这样了
Come here, my beauty.
过来宝贝
Ten thousand thundering typhoons! Come here, you pilfering parakeet!
一千个烂贝壳 逮到你 非宰了你不可
Captain, the bird! Grab it!
船长 那只鸟!抓住它!
Nice work, Snowy! Don't let him go!
干得漂亮 白雪!别让它飞走
You blue blistering barnacles!
臭藤壶
Hang on, Snowy! Snowy, I'm coming!
坚持住 白雪 我来了!
There he is! Stop!
它在这!它在这!停车!
That's right, that's right, come to Daddy.
来啊 来啊 到老爸这来!到老爸这来
Come to Daddy.
到老爸这来!
Gotcha!
逮到你了!
No!
不!
Geronimo!
你们这群野蛮人!
You double-dealing, pilfering parasites!
你这个两面派 顺手牵羊的东西!
Excuse me. Pardon me. Sorry.
打扰了!请原谅我!对不起!
Gotcha!
收到!
The scrolls are lining up.
把纸卷叠加起来
These are hidden numbers.
会出现隐藏的数字
What does it say?
是什么意思呢?
I wouldn't do that if I were you!
如果我是你的话 我可不会那么干的!
Let the bird go.
放开那只鸟
What do you value more, those scrolls or Haddock's life?
你更想要哪个呢?是纸卷还是阿道克的命?
Don't listen to him.
别听他的
You'll never get away with this, you sour-faced sassonack!
你不会从我们手上逃脱的 你这个长着苦瓜脸的家伙
I will kill him.
我会杀了他的
Don't worry about me, Tintin, I'm fine.
别为我担心 丁丁 我很好
Let the bird go now, or this man dies!
马上放开那只鸟 不然他就没命了!
No! Wait!
不!等一下!
You two-timing troglodyte! You simpering son of a po-faced profiteer!
你这个没进化好的猴子!奸商的白痴儿子
Perhaps we should put it to the test. Here's mud in your eye.
也许我们应该扔一下试试?祝你好运
Fathead!
丁丁!
Captain!
船长!
- We're saved! - I love the beach.
- 哦!我们得救了! - 我爱这海滩
- You said you wanted a holiday. - Quite.
- 你不是说你想度假的么 - 是的
Very good.
很好
- Nobody takes my ship! - They've already taken it.
- 没人能抢走我的船! - 他们已经抢走了
Nobody takes my ship twice!
没人能第二次抢走我的船!
We'll show them, won't we, Tintin?
我们会让他们好看的 对不对 丁丁?
All right then, what's the plan?
好吧 接下来怎么办?
There is no plan.
没办法
Of course there's a plan. You've always got a plan.
肯定有办法 你总是有办法的
Not this time.
除了这次
Sakharine has the scrolls. They'll lead him to the treasure.
萨哈林得到了纸卷 那纸卷能让他找到宝藏
It could be anywhere in the world. We'll never see him again.
可能在世界上的任何地方 我们再也找不到他了
It's over.
都结束了
I thought you were an optimist.
我还以为你是一个乐观主义者呢!
Well, you were wrong, weren't you? I'm a realist.
你错了 不是吗?我是一个现实主义者
That's just another name for a quitter.
这只不过是半途而废者的另一个称呼罢了
You can call me what you like.
随便你怎么说我
Don't you get it? We failed.
但你没听明白么?我们失败了
"Failed."
失败了?
There are plenty of others willing to call you a failure.
就算所有人都叫你失败者
A fool. A loser. A hopeless souse!
傻瓜 卢瑟 扶不起的阿斗
Don't you ever say it of yourself.
但是你自己永远也不要这么认为
You send out the wrong signal. That is what people pick up.
你放出错误的讯息 人们就只会抓到它
Do you understand?
你明白吗?
You care about something, you fight for it.
你要为你所在乎的东西去奋斗
You hit a wall, you push through it.
就算前面是墙 你也要穿过去
There's something you need to know about failure, Tintin.
关于失败 你需要了解的还有很多 丁丁
You can never let it defeat you.
它是不会让你解脱的
What did you just say?
你刚才说什么来着?
You hit a wall, you push through it.
就算撞到南墙也要咬牙挺过去?
No, no, no, you said something about sending out a signal.
不 不 不 你刚才说什么发出讯息?
Of course! Captain!
当然!船长
I sent a radio message from the Karaboudjan.
我从卡拉布让 发送过一个广播消息
I know what radio frequency they're transmitting on.
我知道他们传输的无线电频率
Well, how does that help us?
那么 这对我们来说有什么用呢?
All we have to do is send that information to Interpol,
我们要做的就是把那条信息 发送给国际刑警组织
they can track the signals and figure out which way they're headed.
他们可以跟踪信号 并找出他们前进的方向
Here comes Interpol now.
那兄弟俩来了
- Tintin! - Tintin!
- 丁丁! - 丁丁!
Any port they enter we'll know at once.
他们进入任何港口 我们都会马上知道
And we can get there first.
我们会第一个到的
What are we doing here, boss? I don't get it. We're right back where we started.
我们在这干什么 我不明白我们回到启程的地方了
You're to speak of this to no one. Keep your mouths shut.
没人跟你说这个闭上你的嘴
Don't worry. As long as we get our share.
不用担心 只要能得到我们的那份就行
You'll get your share.
你们会得到你们那份的
- Where are you going? - Just guard the ship.
- 你要去哪? - 看好船
Where's the filthy moolah?
那些钱在哪?
Good evening, sir. I trust you had a successful trip abroad.
晚上好 先生!我相信您的海外旅途肯定是一帆风顺
Do I pay you to talk to me?
我花钱让你跟我说话了么?
You don't pay me at all.
你一分钱都没花
What the blazes? Nestor!
这是什么动静?内斯特
Nestor!
内斯特!
Tom! Allan!
汤姆!阿伦!
You blithering idiots, don't just stand there! Do something!
你们这两个白痴 别傻站在那儿 做点什么!
Caught him like a rat in a trap.
就像是瓮中捉鳖啊
Congratulations, gentlemen. He's all yours.
恭喜了 先生们现在由你发落了
Yes! We also have an arrest warrant issued by both Interpol and the FBI.
是的 我们也有国际刑警组织和FBI发出的逮捕令
- Your friend who got shot... - Barnaby.
- 你那个中枪的朋友 - 巴纳
He was one of their agents. Hot on Sakharine's trail from the start.
他是其中的一名特工 从一开始就是萨哈林的跟班
It still doesn't make sense.
这还是说不通啊
He has the key to the treasure of the Unicorn,
他掌握着通往某处海洋深处
which is sitting somewhere on the ocean floor.
独角兽号宝藏的关键
Why would he come back home?
他为什么要回来呢?
Right.
好吧
- Sakharine? - Sakharine?
- 萨哈林? - 萨哈林?
That's Mr Sakharine to you.
你们应该叫我萨哈林先生
Hold it.
不许动
- Look out! - What...
- 小心! - 怎么回事?
Oh, no!
哦 不!
Allan! Allan, get me down!
阿伦 放我下来
What? Not that way!
什么?不是往这边!
Not that way, you fool, the other way!
不是往这边 你个白痴!往另一边!
Right.
好吧
Look out!
小心!
Good Lord! Come on!
我们得离开这儿
Close but no cigar!
差不多 但是还不够准确!
- Red Rackham! - That's right. My ancestor.
- 红色拉克姆 - 没错 那是我的祖先
Just as Sir Francis was yours.
就像你的弗朗西斯爵士一样
Unfinished business.
这就是未了结的宿命
I'm glad you know the truth, Haddock. Until you could remember,
噢 我很高兴你知道真相 阿道克
killing you wouldn't have been this much fun.
如果你想不起来的话 杀你也不会这么有意思的
Who gave you permission to board my ship?
谁允许你登上我的船的?
I don't need it.
我不需要允许
I've never needed it.
我从来不需要
The legend says only a Haddock can discover the secret of the Unicorn,
传说只有阿道克后人 才能发现独角兽号的秘密
but it took a Rackham to get the job done.
但却是拉克姆的后人 搞定了这件事
So you've lost again, Haddock.
看来你又输了 阿道克
That's right. Why don't you have a drink?
那么!你为什么不喝一杯呢?
That's all you've got left, isn't it?
这是你唯一能做的了 不是么?
Everything that was rightfully yours is now mine.
所有你应得的东西现在都是我的了
Including this ship.
包括这船在内
Thundering typhoons. Nobody takes my ship.
臭藤壶 没人能夺走我的船
We have you now, you devil.
逮到你了 坏蛋
- You are under arrest. - To be precise,
- 你被捕了 - 确切的说
you are under arrest.
你被捕了
Do you see?
你看见没?
Blistering barnacles, they're coordinates.
臭藤壶!是坐标!
It took all three scrolls to form the numbers.
需要三张纸卷来组合出这些数字
Latitude and longitude.
经度和纬度
That is it. That's the location of the treasure.
就是它!这就是宝藏的位置了!
We did it!
我们成功了!
Almost there, Mr Tintin!
马上到了 丁丁先生
A nudge to starboard should do it.
右转弯就到了
Are you sure we're on course?
你确定我们走对了么?
Trust me, laddie.
相信我没错的 小伙子
I know these parts like the back of my hand.
我对这一带了如指掌!
Starboard! Quickly! Quickly!
右转 快 快!
Aye, Captain, starboard it is!
喂 船长 右转这
All stop!
停!
Marlinspike Hall.
马林斯派克大厅
Those coordinates lead here.
坐标指的是这
And this is where Sir Francis hid it?
弗朗西斯爵士把它藏这了么?
I thought the treasure went down with the ship.
我本以为宝藏会随沉船一起
Master Haddock, Mr Tintin, I've been expecting you.
阿道克主人 丁丁先生 我已经恭候多时了
Welcome to Marlinspike Hall.
欢迎来到马林斯派克大厅
Will you look at this place?
看看这个地方啊!
I don't think it's changed at all since I was a wee boy.
从我小时候到现在 真是一点没变啊
And may I say, sir, how much I'm looking forward
请允许我说 先生 我是多么地希望
to having a Haddock back in charge of the estate.
阿道克人能回来重掌这里
You'll be waiting a long time, Nestor. There's no way I could afford to live here!
让你久等了 内斯特 我可住不起这种地方啊
Well, Captain, you know the house.
那么 船长 你了解这房子
Where do we start?
我们从哪儿开始?
Is the cellar still here?
地下室 在这边
No, no, no, no, this isn't it.
不 不 不是这儿
I meant the other cellar.
我是说另外的地下室
I'm sorry, sir, there is no "other cellar."
对不起 只有这一个地下室
It was bigger than this.
比这个要大一些
Snowy.
白雪!
Snowy, where are you?
白雪 你在哪?
No, Hector.
不 赫克托
Hector.
赫克托
Captain, help me.
船长 救我
Heel, boy.
留意 小子
Snowy?
白雪
Just like you said, Captain.
就像你说的 船长
You hit a wall...
就算前面是墙
you push through it.
你也要穿过去
My grandfather must have walled it up before he lost the house.
我爷爷一定是在失去这房子之前 把它封起来了
"And then shines forth the Eagle's Cross."
墙上闪闪发光的 一定就是鹰之十字架了
Well, I can see the cross, but where's the eagle?
能看见十字架 但是没有鹰啊?
St John the Evangelist,
记载中传教士圣约翰
who was always depicted with an eagle.
总是和鹰在一起的
And he's called the Eagle of Patmos.
他被叫做帕特摩斯之鹰
He is the eagle.
他就是鹰
What's he trying to tell us, Captain?
但他想要告诉我们什么呢?
I'm at a loss.
我很不解
That island, the one in the middle, that doesn't exist.
中间这个岛 根本不存在
How do you know?
你怎么知道?
Because I've sailed those waters countless times.
因为我曾在这里 巡游了无数次
I've been there. It's a mistake.
这上面标错了
What if it isn't?
如果没标错呢?
Sir Francis wanted his inheritance to go to a man
弗朗西斯爵士要保护它的遗产
who was worthy of it.
让一个值得拥有它的人来继承
A man like himself, who knows the seas like the back of his hand.
一个像他自己那样对大海了如指掌的人
A man who could look at a globe
一个能在地球仪上看一眼
and tell if one tiny island
就能说出一个小岛
was out of place.
是否存在的人
Blistering treasure.
价值连城的珠宝
It's Red Rackham's barnacles!
这就是红色拉克姆的宝藏
What is this?
这是什么?
Just a wee tipple.
来一小杯
A toast to our good fortune.
为好运干杯
That's better.
噢 好多了!
It's odd, really. You would've thought,
奇怪 你不觉得经历艰难险阻之后
after all the fuss and bother, there would've been more.
应该能多点么
- More of what? - Red Rackham's treasure.
- 什么多点? - 红色拉克姆的宝藏
I mean, by your account, he looted half of South America. I just thought...
我是说按你的说法 他掠夺了半个南美!我只是觉得
Never mind. There's plenty to go around.
啊 无所谓了 这些也足够多了
It's a funny old life, eh?
噢 那时的生活真有趣
Well, you've got your story for your newspaper.
现在你有可以上报纸的 好故事可写了
All's well that ends well.
吉人自有天相啊
It's not ended.
还没结束呢
Sir Francis left another clue at the bottom of the globe.
弗朗西斯爵士在地球仪底部留下了另一个线索
- A clue to what? - Four hundredweight of gold,
- 什么的线索? - 四百英担的黄金
just lying at the bottom of the sea.
就沉睡在海底
How's your thirst for adventure, Captain?
你对冒险的渴望度有多高 船长?
Unquenchable, Tintin.
无穷无尽 丁丁